<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"> <channel><title>lab.rebma.io Notebook</title><description>A collection fo thoughts and resources for Makers.</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/</link><atom:link href="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><docs>https://github.com/rebma-io/lab</docs><language>en-None</language> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:39:48 -0000</pubDate> <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:39:48 -0000</lastBuildDate> <ttl>1440</ttl> <generator>MkDocs RSS plugin - v1.7.0</generator> <image> <url>https://lab.rebma.io/assets/rebma-io-logo-black.png</url> <title>lab.rebma.io Notebook</title><link>https://lab.rebma.io/</link> </image> <item> <title>The Lab</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;The Lab&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: If you have a request, please open a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rebma-io/lab/issues&#34;&gt;GithubIssue&lt;/a&gt;, and I&#39;ll see what I cando. I try to limit my discussion to things I am somewhat confidentabout. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The overall goal of this is to provide as much research, thoughts, plans, andoverall discovered detritus as possible to (hopefully) help someone elsecomplete a project. It is organized into a few top-level sections, fromleft to right:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Projects. As I find time, there will be documentation of various projects here. They could be hardware, software, or both.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Electronics. Resources about electronics. Starting with fundamentals and working up through more advanced stuff.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mechanical. What it means to make something in the real world, stick it together, and make it move (or not move) as you see fit.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;3D Stuff. My work in 3D printing, though mostly just small things to make life easier.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Software. References for writing software, both general, and more specifically for Python.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Organization. How to keep a workshop organized. I&#39;m not great at this, but I&#39;ve developed a few patterns.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tools. Mostly hand tools.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Resources. Other places to find things.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tags. I&#39;m trying to get better at tagging resources, so you can find an &#34;index&#34; of sorts here.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;About. A bit about me.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also think it&#39;s worth talking about what it means to be a maker,though. I &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ER7rhQ7N69k&#34;&gt;think Adam Savage summed it upbest&lt;/a&gt;, but it comes down tohis 10 commandments of the maker:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make something.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make something useful.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start right now.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find a project.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ask for help, advice, and feedback.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Share.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Recognize that discouragement and failure is part of the project.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Measure carefully.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Make things for other people.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use more cooling fluid.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/</guid> </item> <item> <title>About</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;rebma.io logo&#34; src=&#34;assets/rebma-io-logo-black.png&#34;&gt;{: width=240 align=right }&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;rebma.io is a label for Maker projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;WARNING: &lt;strong&gt;Not a Professional Engineer&lt;/strong&gt; While I have been an engineerof various forms for the last 30+ years, I am not a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regulation_and_licensure_in_engineering&#34;&gt;professionalengineer&lt;/a&gt;,and much of the information here is self-taught and not formallyeducated. Just keep that in mind as you read. My curiosity may be nearlylimitless, but my understanding always has limits. I&#39;ll try to pointthese out wherever I can.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Why&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being a maker means learning a dizzying number of skills, and as part of thespirit of the community I wanted to share things that I&#39;ve learned, found, andotherwise hope others might find some use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Who&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The content in this collection is written by Chris Petrilli. An engineer of 30years in the tech business working in software, security, and embeddedsystems. Where the content comes from someone else, I have endeavoured tomake sure it is linked to the original source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Amazon, Affiliate Links and Such&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are no affiliate links on this website. I don&#39;t get any money off ofanything you click on. I&#39;ve also tried to point people at the originalmanufacturer, rather than just throw it at Amazon. Amazon can be a life saverfor hard to find things, but they&#39;re still not a particularly ethicalorganization to do business with.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do use some basic analytics (powered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://usefathom.com&#34;&gt;FathomAnalytics&lt;/a&gt;), which is &lt;a href=&#34;https://usefathom.com/privacy-focused-web-analytics&#34;&gt;much more privacyfocused&lt;/a&gt;, and only collectsthe barest minimum of information. I don&#39;t even see IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Built With&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The site is built using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mkdocs.org&#34;&gt;MkDocs&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squidfunk.github.io/mkdocs-material/&#34;&gt;Material forMkDocs&lt;/a&gt; theme (although it&#39;s muchbigger than that). It is edited (primarily) in &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com&#34;&gt;Visual StudioCode&lt;/a&gt;, written in&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markdownguide.org&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; and also using &lt;a href=&#34;https://jupyter.org&#34;&gt;Jupyternotebooks&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, it is hosted on Github Pages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, throughout, you&#39;ll find interactive circuit simulators.These were built on top of Paul Falstad&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.falstad.com/circuit/&#34;&gt;brilliantcircuitjs&lt;/a&gt;. I also took a bunch of theexample circuits and have used them as a starting point for discussion.More details can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;electronics/simulating-circuits.md&#34;&gt;thispage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/about/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/about/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Changelog or What&#39;s New</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Changelog or What&#39;s New&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: &lt;strong&gt;What is a Changelog?&lt;/strong&gt; A&lt;a href=&#34;https://keepachangelog.com/en/1.0.0/&#34;&gt;changelog&lt;/a&gt; is a curated list ofnotable changes, typically ordered by date or version. For thepurposes of this site, I&#39;m going to try and add an entry anytime I addor substantially update something. I thought about just stuffing theGit logs into this, but that has a lot more noise in it than mostpeople want to read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This changelog will be kept in reverse chronological order, with thenewest things on top. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you wish to use an &lt;a href=&#34;https://newsblur.com/&#34;&gt;RSS reader&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;youshould&lt;/em&gt;, there is an RSS feed of both &lt;a href=&#34;/feed_rss_created.xml&#34;&gt;newthings&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/feed_rss_updated.xml&#34;&gt;updatedthings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-12-27&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wrote up the &lt;a href=&#34;electronics/connectors/standard-pmod.md&#34;&gt;Pmod &#34;standard&#34;&lt;/a&gt; since I&#39;ve found it a bit confusing at times, and it&#39;s quite common in the FPGA world. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Covered &lt;a href=&#34;electronics/logic-levels.md&#34;&gt;logic levels&lt;/a&gt; with a bit on the 74-series families that implement them since they&#39;re the most common basic blocks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-12-13&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added &lt;a href=&#34;3d/my-designs.md&#34;&gt;a new design&lt;/a&gt; for the Rigol DHO800/900 series scopes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-12-01&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;a href=&#34;3d/fusion360.md#default-user-parameters&#34;&gt;Fusion360 CSV to import for metric fasteners&lt;/a&gt;. This now includes M2-M12 clearance holes in normal, close, and loose.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-11-11&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Started a little &lt;a href=&#34;til.md&#34;&gt;today I learned&lt;/a&gt; page to collect some little things. I really need to figure out how to make it a bit more discoverable, but for now, I just want to make it super simple.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-10-20&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added a quick tip from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/blondihacks&#34;&gt;Blondihacks&lt;/a&gt; for storing sandpaper and emery cloth.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-09-11&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Started collection &lt;a href=&#34;organization/random-tips-and-tricks.md&#34;&gt;tips and tricks&lt;/a&gt; around organization that I&#39;ve seen.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-09-09&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&#34;tools/workstation.md&#34;&gt;writeup&lt;/a&gt; of my workstation setup. Nothing too fancy, but I figured it&#39;d be an interesting discussion give it&#39;s been recently updated.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added a &lt;a href=&#34;3D/fusion360.md#add-ons-and-extensibility&#34;&gt;few new extensions&lt;/a&gt; to my Fusion 360 information.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-09-03&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wrote up &lt;a href=&#34;projects/decrunching-telescoping-gauges/index.md&#34;&gt;cleaning up some cheap telescoping hole gauges&lt;/a&gt; I picked up cheap at a garage sale.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-09-01&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;electronics/pcb/supplier-comparison.md&#34;&gt;Wrote up my experiment with multiple PCB suppliers&lt;/a&gt;. I sent the same small PCB to 3 different suppliers and saw how they dealt with it, and what they produced.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;organization/inventory.md#storage-boxes&#34;&gt;Documented a new approach to sorting box inventory&lt;/a&gt; that seems to be really working well for me. It does require a little specialized equipment, but it&#39;s not prohibitively expensive.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-08-23&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added a small &lt;a href=&#34;electronics/random-tips-and-tricks.md#parts-management&#34;&gt;tip&lt;/a&gt; about sorting SMD parts and reducing static cling.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Minor link cleanup. There were a few broken links.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-08-21&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;resources/video.md&#34;&gt;A few new YouTube channels&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;tools/guides/precision-voltage-and-current-signal-generator.md&#34;&gt;Added some information&lt;/a&gt; about a rather inexpensive, but precision current and voltage source, so long as you can work within its limits.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Updated the &lt;a href=&#34;https://squidfunk.github.io/mkdocs-material/changelog/#9.2.1&#34;&gt;mkdocs-material&lt;/a&gt; to 9.2.1, which includes all of 9.2.0 from the 9.1 release. This also brought in mkdocs v1.5.2. I also needed to update &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/greenape/mknotebooks/releases/tag/0.8.0&#34;&gt;mknotebooks&lt;/a&gt; to v0.8.0 to fix an import issue.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added a quick update to the &lt;a href=&#34;organization/labeling.md#labeling&#34;&gt;labeling&lt;/a&gt; section about how to keep all the labels together to simplify batch printing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-08-20&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;projects/replacement-microscope-base/index.md&#34;&gt;Wrote up the project&lt;/a&gt; to replace the base of my Joyalens JL-249 10.1&#34; video microscope. This added a heavy magnetic steel base as a replacement. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-08-15&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added a few new barcode-related &lt;a href=&#34;software/python/libraries.md&#34;&gt;Python libraries&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-08-14&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added an &lt;a href=&#34;software/barcode-formats.md&#34;&gt;introduction to barcodes&lt;/a&gt;, both 1D and 2D. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-07-28&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added information on the &lt;a href=&#34;organization/sortimo.md&#34;&gt;Bosch-Sortimo system&lt;/a&gt;, including labeling and other details.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-07-25&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added information on &lt;a href=&#34;electronics/reference-designators.md&#34;&gt;reference designators&lt;/a&gt; for schematics. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-07-20&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added ITO glass to the &lt;a href=&#34;mechanical/materials.md&#34;&gt;interesting materials&lt;/a&gt; section. Super fun material used in touch screens and other applications.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added diagrams showing a visual example of the &lt;a href=&#34;mechanical/fit.md&#34;&gt;types of fit&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some coverage of screws, specifically. This includes a discussion of the various types, materials, thread variations, and uses. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;2023-07-14&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Formalized the structure of the site. Previously, I had been just letting MkDocs figure it out from directory structure, but this often led to some weird organization. While it&#39;s more work to keep a manual nav structure up-to-date, I think it will be more useful as a consumer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Added an RSS feed for &lt;a href=&#34;/feed_rss_updated.xml&#34;&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/feed_rss_created.xml&#34;&gt;creations&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href=&#34;[Title](https://github.com/guts/mkdocs-rss-plugin)&#34;&gt;mkdocs-rss-plugin&lt;/a&gt;. Thank you to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz&#34;&gt;Aaron Schwartz&lt;/a&gt;, who was taken too soon (f- you MIT and feds), and others who contributed to this amazing tech.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/changelog/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/changelog/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Secret Test Page</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Secret Test Page&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;WARNING: &lt;strong&gt;Ignore This&lt;/strong&gt; There is nothing of interest here, this is justwhere I play with configuration things for the site itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FILE_NOT_FOUND&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/secret-test/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/secret-test/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Today I Learned</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Today I Learned&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: A lot of times, I find little bits of information that aren&#39;treally enough to write an entire thing about, but I&#39;d like to share themwith people. That&#39;s what this little section is for. The idea was&lt;a href=&#34;https://til.simonwillison.net/&#34;&gt;inspired by Simon Willison&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2024-02-02&lt;/em&gt;. As of 7.0.5 (I think) of KiCad on macOS, they have disabled support for the Space Mouse due to some perceived flakiness. I&#39;m unclear what this is given I&#39;ve never experienced anything but rock solid support in things like Fusion and Solidworks. It is possible to get it back by following the instructions in &lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/kicad/code/kicad/-/issues/14847&#34;&gt;this ticket&lt;/a&gt;, which is completely not obvious.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2023-11-23&lt;/em&gt;. Learning to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcmaster.com/products/hole-gauges/economy-telescoping-bore-gauge-sets/&#34;&gt;telescoping bore gauges&lt;/a&gt; can be super challenging. It requires developing a &lt;em&gt;feel&lt;/em&gt; for when it&#39;s properly situated. Someone mentioned getting some known good and precise bores to work with. Some examples were bronze bearings, which are both inexpensive and very precisely made.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;2023-11-11&lt;/em&gt;. I&#39;ve been digging into Ada recently, and had a problem getting &lt;a href=&#34;https://alire.ada.dev/&#34;&gt;Alire&lt;/a&gt; and Visual Studio Code to play nicely with one another. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://tech.lgbt/@robdaemon&#34;&gt;Rob&lt;/a&gt; for the tip that you need to start VSC with &lt;code&gt;alr exec -- code .&lt;/code&gt; in the directory with the Ada Project&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/til/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/til/</guid> </item> <item> <title>3D Things</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;3D Things&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;!-- TODO:* Discus places to find files, Printables, Thingaverse, Thangs, etc.--&gt;&lt;p&gt;3D modeling and printing is an enormously versatile and powerful area,but it&#39;s also a complicated one. I&#39;ve tried to collect a few thingstogether that will hopefully be of some assistance. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;filament.md&#34;&gt;Filament&lt;/a&gt;. Contains a discussion of filament brands and storage. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;fusion360.md&#34;&gt;Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;. Tips and tricks around the use of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/overview?term=1-YEAR&amp;amp;tab=subscription&#34;&gt;Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;joining-parts.md&#34;&gt;Joining Parts Together&lt;/a&gt;. Not everything can be printed as a single piece, so how do you stick them together?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;modeling-tools.md&#34;&gt;Modeling Tools&lt;/a&gt;. Discussion of modeling tools besides Fusion 360.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;octoprint.md&#34;&gt;Octoprint&lt;/a&gt;. Octoprint lets you control a 3D printer over the network, and even from around the world.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;parametric-parameters.md&#34;&gt;Parametric Parameters&lt;/a&gt;. One of the most powerful parts of parametric modeling tools, like Fusion 360 or SOLIDWORKS, is the ability to drive everything based on adjustable parameters. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;prusa.md&#34;&gt;Prusa 3D Printers&lt;/a&gt;. Tips and tricks around Prusa printers, specifically the MINI+.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;solidworks.md&#34;&gt;3DEXPERIENCE SOLIDWORKS&lt;/a&gt;. A few little details about SOLIDWORKS.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3rd Party Resources&lt;/h2&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Methodology</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Design Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are three major approaches to how you go about building out anentire product/design. Start at the top, start at the bottom, or startin the middle. Let&#39;s try and quickly define them:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Fusion 360 supports all of these, it &lt;em&gt;wants&lt;/em&gt; to use eithertop-down or middle-out. No approach is pure, though, and this is just away to think about the process rather than some strict rule.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Top-Down&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For top-down designs, the parts&#39; shapes, sizes, and locations aredesigned in the larger assembly. For example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can model a bracket so it is always the correct size to holda motor, even if you move the motor. The system will automaticallyresizes the motor bracket. This is helpful for parts like brackets,fixtures, and housings, whose purpose is largely to hold other partsin their correct positions. You can also use top-down design oncertain features (such as locating pins) of otherwise bottom-up parts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The advantage of top-down design is that much less rework is needed whendesign changes occur. The parts know how to update themselves based onthe way you created them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use top-down design techniques on certain features of a part,complete parts, or entire assemblies. In practice, designers typicallyuse top-down techniques to lay out their assemblies and to capture keyaspects of custom parts specific to their assemblies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Bottom-Up&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bottom-up design is the traditional &#34;part first&#34; method. You firstdesign and model parts, then insert them into an assembly and use matesto position the parts. To change the parts, you must edit themindividually. These changes are then promoted to the assembly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bottom-up design is the preferred technique for off-the-shelf parts, orstandard components like hardware, pulleys, motors, etc. These parts donot change their shape and size based on your design unless you choose adifferent component.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Middle-Out&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The answer, as always, is often somewhere in the middle. Typically, youbegin with some existing components and design other parts as requiredaround them. For example, after looking at the design in your head, oron paper, you might insert or create the grounded (base/immovable)component. As you develop the assembly, place existing components orcreate new ones in place, as required.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/design-methodology/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/design-methodology/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Filament</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Filament&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Filament Brands&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had good luck with a decent number of filaments that I can recommendwithout reservation:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://prusament.com/&#34;&gt;Prusament PLA/PETG&lt;/a&gt;. Pricey, but excellent quality.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printedsolid.com/collections/1-75mm-jessie&#34;&gt;Jessie PLA&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve only used the PLA, but the quality is outstanding and the price is excellent..&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://us.polymaker.com/&#34;&gt;Polymaker&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve mostly used the PolyLite PLA Pro and PolyTerra PLA. I do love (!) their &lt;a href=&#34;https://app.powerbi.com/view?r=eyJrIjoiOGIxOTRjM2EtMGVhYS00ZDEwLWJmNTktYTlkYzRlOWY2Nzk2IiwidCI6IjUzOTgwYzA1LWI4MWYtNDM2My04OWNiLTU3NzRiMWFlYWYyZCIsImMiOjEwfQ%3D%3D&#34;&gt;material comparison site&lt;/a&gt;, and more manufacturers should do this. Their silks are lovely, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://us.polymaker.com/products/polylite-starlight-pla&#34;&gt;starlight mercury&lt;/a&gt; is pretty much hands-down favorite color.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elegoo.com/products/elegoo-pla-filament-1-75mm-3d-printer-filament-1kg-spool-2-2-lbs&#34;&gt;Elegoo&lt;/a&gt;. Boring PLA. But also reliable and very inexpensive. It&#39;s made up a lot of the bulk printing for things like black.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hatchbox3d.com/&#34;&gt;Hatchbox&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve used their matte and transparent filaments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proto-pasta.com/&#34;&gt;Protopasta&lt;/a&gt;. My home for fun and bizarre filaments. I have some of their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proto-pasta.com/collections/all/feature_electrically-conductive&#34;&gt;conductive&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proto-pasta.com/collections/all/contents_metal-powder&#34;&gt;metal-filled&lt;/a&gt;. Their prices aren&#39;t the cheapest, but the quality is there.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://overture3d.com/products/overturepla&#34;&gt;Overture&lt;/a&gt;. Just a general low-price quality filament.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sainsmart.com/collections/tpu-filament&#34;&gt;Sainsmart TPU&lt;/a&gt;. TPU is a flexible filament, and this has been a reasonably successful one for a Bowden-tube loving 3d printer.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.esun3d.com/eclean-product/&#34;&gt;eSun cleaning filament&lt;/a&gt;. I only use their cleaning filament, but it&#39;s top notch.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Filament Drying and Storage&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A lot of filaments are hygroscopic, meaning they&#39;ll absorb water overtime. This can lead to a lot of problems with printing, and you cansometimes hear the crackle of the water boiling away in the heater.Because of this, I take a two-pronged strategy:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Storage of filament in a dry box.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Usage of a heater when printing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Dry Box Design&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For storage, I use some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.irisusainc.com/collections/weathertight/products/60-quart-weathertight-multi-purpose-storage-box-clear-with-blue-buckles-3-pack&#34;&gt;60qt storagebox&lt;/a&gt;.They are a nice size, easy to maneuver, and have foam gaskets to help reduce airinfiltration. Inside of that I&#39;ve 3d printed a pair of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/1367-malolos-silica-gel-desiccant-containers&#34;&gt;75mm containers fordesiccant&lt;/a&gt;(print the funnel and plug trust me), and filled it with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/dp/B013L31PQ0&#34;&gt;color-changing silicadesiccant&lt;/a&gt;. So far, this has managed tokeep the RH somewhere between 20-30%. I monitor the boxes with an inexpensive&lt;a href=&#34;https://buythermopro.com/product/tp49/&#34;&gt;ThermoPro TP49&lt;/a&gt; temperature andhumidity monitor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Filament Heater&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When printing, I move the filament into a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sunlu.com/products/new-version-sunlu-filadryer-s2&#34;&gt;SunLu filament dryerv2&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve hadsome issues with it getting pulled towards the printer, and even tipping over,but I&#39;ve mostly resolved that by 1) feeding the filament from the bottom, notthe top (think toilet paper roll); 2) adding some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B071WP8HGP/&#34;&gt;wheelweights&lt;/a&gt; to give it some moreheft. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/filament/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/filament/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Fusion 360</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Fusion 360&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/overview&#34;&gt;Fusion360&lt;/a&gt; for all ofmy 3D and ECAD work. I&#39;m trying to collect together things I&#39;ve learned,and recommendations here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Rules for Success&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are two critical rules that the community has developed over theyears, and I highly recommend following them:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Everything goes into a component.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Everything has a name.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&#39;s take the two separately.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Rule #1: Components&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Components are a container for sketches, geometry, joint origins, bodies, etc.This helps organize things. This makes it much easier to think about andabstract your project. Think of a component as a part. There are a few otheradvantages to using components extensively:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The joints in the Assembly menu only work with components.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drawings can only be created from components. On activation, the timeline is filtered. This means it will only show items in the timeline that pertain to that component. The timeline on a big project can become unwieldy, and this will make the quickly growing timeline much easier to work with.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you export a component with &#34;save as&#34; Fusion 360 will also export the complete parametric design history.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only components show on the BOM.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only components can be added to &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.autodesk.com/view/fusion360/ENU/?guid=SLD-CREATE-SELECTION-SETS&#34;&gt;selection sets&lt;/a&gt;. Selection sets are a way to &#34;name&#34; a specific group of items that you can refer to again and again consistently.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Only components can be isolated. This allows you to make everything but one component &#34;disappear&#34; from the design, and ensure you don&#39;t accidentally affect them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You can make copies of a component, but keep linked changes (or not if you want). This can be super helpful in larger assemblies. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s also a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/blog/5-things-you-should-know-about-components-and-bodies/&#34;&gt;writeup&lt;/a&gt;on the difference between components and bodies. This is super importantto understand. Also, some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/blog/5-time-saving-strategies-assembly-design/&#34;&gt;strategies for usingcomponents&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that this is a soft rule, not a hard rule. Following it blindly,like so many rules, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/blog/quick-tip-rule-1-oversight/&#34;&gt;can result infailure&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Rule #2: Names&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Name your things. Most everything can be named in Fusion 360, but you&lt;em&gt;definitely&lt;/em&gt; want to name these things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sketches&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bodies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Construction planes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Section analysis&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Views&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Components&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also name extrusions, chamfers, and a lot of other things.Whether you name this or not is up to you, but if you do name them, thenin the design history timeline, you&#39;ll see more information, which maymake it easier to navigate larger timelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, name them clearly, and I tend to use somewhat long-winded names, oftengoing from coarse to fine granularity. If this is something&#34;structured&#34;, I might even include &lt;a href=&#34;../organization/part-numbers.md&#34;&gt;partnumbers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Tips and Tricks&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/blog/quick-tip-the-s-key/&#34;&gt;Learn to use the S-key functionality&lt;/a&gt;. This is a quick way to search for commands and execute them, or activate a tool. You can also pin commonly used commands to the menu. One thing to be aware of is that, for &lt;em&gt;some reason&lt;/em&gt;, Fusion 360 will show you 3D commands when you&#39;re in 2D sketches, and so you need to be cognizant of the difference and the different icon.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/support/technical/article/caas/sfdcarticles/sfdcarticles/How-to-Toggle-Component-Cycling-Color-in-Fusion-360.html&#34;&gt;Component color cycling&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing way to view your models when you have a bunch of components. Rather than just using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.autodesk.com/view/fusion360/ENU/?guid=GUID-D59206EC-875D-4890-8088-AD23E5364951&#34;&gt;appearance&lt;/a&gt;, it ensures that every component is distinct from all the ones around it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;All of the analysis capabilities are insanely useful, and you should familiarize yourself with them, but I would definitely start with &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.autodesk.com/view/fusion360/ENU/?guid=SLD-SECTION-ANALYSIS&#34;&gt;section analysis&lt;/a&gt;, which allows you to cut through the component and see what is going on inside. This will also show how multiple components interact clearly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Add-Ons and Extensibility&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing I really like about Fusion360 is that there&#39;s an extensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Home/Index&#34;&gt;ecosystemof apps&lt;/a&gt; or add-ons that allowyou to extend the tool in fun and pretty amazing ways. Similar to AutoCAD,nearly everything inside Fusion360 is &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.autodesk.com/view/fusion360/ENU/?guid=GUID-C1545D80-D804-4CF3-886D-9B5C54B2D7A2&#34;&gt;exposed programmatically&lt;/a&gt;. You can writeextensions in either Python or C++ (although the electronics design still usesthe EAGLE &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.autodesk.com/view/fusion360/ENU/?guid=GUID-C1545D80-D804-4CF3-886D-9B5C54B2D7A2&#34;&gt;user languageprogramming&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use a few plugins regularly:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=2942207745179825936&#34;&gt;3D Print Plus&lt;/a&gt;. This provides a much more advanced way to send STL to a slicer if you don&#39;t want to use the FFF slicing capabilities inside Fusion360 itself. The only &#34;problem&#34; is that it can only send a single body at a time, which, if you want to print a bunch of bodies, can be painful. There is a pro version, but I haven&#39;t needed the features (although I may buy just to support the author).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=156700835167123223&#34;&gt;AnyShortcut&lt;/a&gt;. This allows you to create a keyboard shortcut for things in Fusion 360 that don&#39;t have one. This is especially useful in integrating with an El Gato Stream Deck.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=9068625559069345798&#34;&gt;Additive Assistant&lt;/a&gt;. Provides a bunch of additional analysis tools for FFF manufacturing around things like overhang, warp, poor bed adhesion, etc. This runs in the Design workspace.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=7497198800232664541&#34;&gt;DirectName&lt;/a&gt;. Rule #1: thou shalt always use components. Rule #2: name your stuff. This prompts you to name everything (bodies, features, sketches, etc) immediately, rather than creating them and then requiring you to go back and rename them. While it is, initially, annoying, it sure does help keep things clean and understandable in the timeline.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=1864820821708132049&#34;&gt;Duplicate Components&lt;/a&gt;. Automates the steps for creating instances or creating duplicate components in a design. This is great when you want to include things like screws in your designs.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=1236778940008086660&#34;&gt;GFGearGenerator&lt;/a&gt;. Lets you design gears in 3D very simply. Won&#39;t go into anything super-exotic, but it solves problems quickly.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=789800822168335025&#34;&gt;Install from Github&lt;/a&gt;. Not everything is on the Autodesk &#34;store&#34;. There&#39;s a bunch of things you can find on Github. This takes the project URL and installs it all for you automatically. It doesn&#39;t, unfortunately, automatically update the plugin, but instead just installs a zip of the current state.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=5188175718375703395&#34;&gt;No Component Warn&lt;/a&gt;. Nanny plugin to make sure you always put things in a component (rude #1). It also catches mistakes where you&#39;re using the wrong component and adding something to it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=1801418194626000805&#34;&gt;Parameters I/O&lt;/a&gt;. Allows you to import/export user parameters as a CSV. This is great way to get a bunch of &#34;default&#34; parameters. &lt;a href=&#34;#default-user-parameters&#34;&gt;See below for mine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=2114937992453312456&#34;&gt;ParametricText&lt;/a&gt;. Provides parameters for text. Weirdly, this is something you can&#39;t do with the regular parameters. It also has access to variables that you can use which are covered in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://parametrictext.readthedocs.io/en/stable/&#34;&gt;excellent documentation&lt;/a&gt;. Use it. Use it all the time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=5446990520022318629&#34;&gt;SnapEDA&lt;/a&gt;. Provides access (Windows only) to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.snapeda.com/&#34;&gt;SnapEDA&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s extensive library of components. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=1006119760063675415&#34;&gt;Voronoi&lt;/a&gt;. Helps you generate &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Voronoi_diagram&#34;&gt;Voronoi diagrams&lt;/a&gt;. The plugin isn&#39;t particularly great, and it has a tendency to put the generated diagrams in entirely the wrong plane, but it&#39;s free and generates decent quality results that you can move where you need them.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;!-- TODO: Evaluate Dogbone add-on https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=3534533763590670806TODO: Evaluate NetApp add-onTODO: Evaluate Any Shortcuts add-on https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=156700835167123223TODO: Evaluate Gridfinity Generator https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=7197558650811789--&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Personal License v Subscription&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autodesk has a &#34;free&#34; (as in beer) license available for &#34;personal use&#34;. Whilethey have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/personal&#34;&gt;rudimentarycomparison&lt;/a&gt;, there are afew things that absolutely drove me to spend the larger sum for a normalsubscription: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Max of 10 documents in read-write and everything else read-only. And you have to manually manage it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Super-limited electronics. 2 schematics and 2 layers. Nothing more.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Drawings can only have a single sheet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No simulation capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;No access to cloud services (which aren&#39;t cheap, but are super powerful).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For getting started, though, it&#39;s 100% worth starting with the personal licenseand figuring out if this is something you&#39;re serious enough about to drop the$495.00 :material-update:{ title=&#34;as of 2023-06&#34; }&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xe.com/currencyconverter/convert/?Amount=495.00&amp;amp;From=USD&amp;amp;To=EUR&#34; title=&#34;Convert to other currency&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-solid-money-bill-transfer:&lt;/a&gt; that it will cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Random Bits of Information&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For text, you have to use a TrueType font (ttf), not an OpenType (otf) font, at least in Windows. If you use OTF, you will get errors like &#34;could not retrieve the profiles of the selected text&#34;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://productdesignonline.com/how-to-create-and-use-global-parameters-in-fusion-360/&#34;&gt;How to use global parameters across many different files&lt;/a&gt;, although it&#39;s a pain in the ass.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Learning Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autodesk has a pretty great collection of courses up on Coursera forfree. The ones I&#39;ve looked at are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/introduction-digital-manufacturing-fusion-360&#34;&gt;Introduction to Digital Manufacturing with Autodesk Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/fusion-360-integrated-cad-cam-cae&#34;&gt;Autodesk Fusion 360 Integrated CAD/CAM/CAE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/3d-model-creation-fusion-360&#34;&gt;3D Model Creation with Autodesk Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/engineering-design-process-fusion-360&#34;&gt;Engineering Design Process with Autodesk Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/manufacturing-process-fusion-360&#34;&gt;Manufacturing Process with Autodesk Fusion 360&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;They have a huge number of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/autodesk&#34;&gt;choices forcourses&lt;/a&gt; in a lot of topics,depending on your interest area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3rd Party Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://autodeskfusion360.github.io/&#34;&gt;Autodesk&#39;s Fusion 360 API&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/community/gallery&#34;&gt;Autodesk Community Gallery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://productdesignonline.com/tips-and-tricks/understanding-bodies-and-components-fusion-360-rule-1/&#34;&gt;Understanding bodies and components&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/fusion360/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/fusion360/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Joining Parts</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Joining Parts&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;When joining parts, there&#39;s one question you need to start with: is thisreversible? That will guide you down the path of what technique to use.There are a couple of ways to join parts together, each with trade-offs:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Press fit. Typically non-reversible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Snap fit. Reversible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Glue. Non-reversible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Screws. Reversible.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Press Fit&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you can get the &lt;a href=&#34;/mechanical/fit.md&#34;&gt;mechanical fit&lt;/a&gt; setup correct, then youmay be able to use an interference fit and stick things together without anyother mechanism. Unfortunately, you also run the risk of breaking the partsdoing this, so I strongly advise against it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Snap-Fit&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Snap-fit is a common way of making injection-molded parts fit together,but it can also be used in 3D printing. A snap-fit set of pars usuallyconsists of a protrusion and a mating depression, generating aninterlocking connection that often relies on parts that bend. There aremany guides on creating them, but I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://all3dp.com/2/3d-printing-snap-fit-design-simply-explained/&#34;&gt;thisone&lt;/a&gt;as a start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Glue&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using glue is a great option, and there are three primary glues that arecommonly used:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyanoacrylate&#34;&gt;Cyanoacrylate&lt;/a&gt; (&#34;super glue&#34;)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;UV-set epoxy. I like &lt;a href=&#34;https://bondic-store.com&#34;&gt;Bondic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hot-melt_adhesive&#34;&gt;Hot glue&lt;/a&gt;, which is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermoplastic&#34;&gt;thermopastic&lt;/a&gt;](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thermoplastic) and not a traditional adhesive.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of these has trade-offs, but the first two are the most durable andstrongest. The hot glue is useful for more temporary things, or things wherethere will not be much stress on the joint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Screws&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Screws are a great way to join two or more printed parts together in asemi-permanent fashion. There are a few possibilities in how you can screw themtogether that I&#39;m going to cover here. Stefan over at CNC Kitchen has done a&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cnckitchen.com/blog/helicoils-threaded-insets-and-embedded-nuts-in-3d-prints-strength-amp-strength-assessment&#34;&gt;goodcomparison&lt;/a&gt;of various techniques from a strength perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Just Screw It In&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Honestly, you can just screw it in, and certainly, a&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-tapping_screw&#34;&gt;self-tapping&lt;/a&gt;screws](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self-tapping_screw) should work.Unfortunately, this is not a super repeatable process, and should onlybe used if you plan to remove it once or twice at most.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Tapping Holes&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The next option is to use a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tap_and_die&#34;&gt;tap-and-dieset&lt;/a&gt; pre-cut the threads intothe printed part. This will reduce the tension in the part, and ensure amuch cleaner join as the taps are &lt;em&gt;very sharp&lt;/em&gt;. For the best results,you&#39;ll want to tap the hole twice. The first time using either a plug ortaper tap, and the second time using a bottoming tap. The first willmake sure 90% of the threads are cut, and the bottoming tap will ensurethe last few at the bottom are cut properly. If you try to use abottoming tap by itself, you&#39;ll find that it will struggle to get theinitial bite into the material and stay straight. I&#39;ll be honest,though, that I typically just use one tap and call it &#34;good enough&#34;since the last few threads can be cut by the screw itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help explain it, I made a small video:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/RjGXpc7K3p0&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Threaded Inserts&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favorite is to use brass threaded inserts. These are inserts that are heatset into the printed part and provide a durable and repeatable joint. The ones Ilike are from Stefan at &lt;a href=&#34;https://cnckitchen.store&#34;&gt;CNC Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;, and look likethis: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://cnckitchen.store&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;M3 threaded insert from CNCKitchen&#34; src=&#34;../img/cnc-kitchen-threaded-insert.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also get quality examples from&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcmaster.com/products/threaded-inserts/for-use-in~plastic/&#34;&gt;McMaster-Carr&lt;/a&gt;who stocks an even wider variety in even more materials. There are other brands,but I&#39;ve found these to be of the best quality and have never failed me. You&#39;llalso really want to get the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cnckitchen.store/products/einschmelzhilfen-soldering-tips-m2-m2-5-m3-m4-m5-m6-1-4-m8-100-lead-and-cadmium-free&#34;&gt;solderingtips&lt;/a&gt;that will make it much easier to use (assuming your soldering iron supportseither T18 or 900M tips). You&#39;ll definitely want to print the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/167924-case-for-cnc-kitchen-threaded-inserts-soldering-ti&#34;&gt;storagecase&lt;/a&gt;and if you happen to have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dremel.com/us/en/p/220-01-26150220aa&#34;&gt;Dremel 220-01workstation&lt;/a&gt;, you can print an&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/405918-heat-set-insert-press-hakko-fx888-dremel-workstati&#34;&gt;adapter&lt;/a&gt; that will let you use it todepress your soldering iron and ensure a clean insert at the correct angle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hackaday has &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackaday.com/2019/02/28/threading-3d-printed-parts-how-to-use-heat-set-inserts/&#34;&gt;a greatarticle&lt;/a&gt;detailing how to design parts for threaded inserts and how to properly installthem. I find using a temperature about 5C above the filament print temperatureworks well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TODO: Video showing inserting these by hand and also using the Dremelworkstation with adapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/joining-parts/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/joining-parts/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Choosing Modeling Tools</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Modeling Tools&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before discussing 3D modeling tools, I wanted to put out some of the things thatI was looking for in a tool:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Parametric. The tool absolutely must be built on the idea of parametric design, and allow for ongoing evolution by adjusting the parameters and then re-solving the design.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Integrated MCAD/ECAD. When building something that combines something like 3D printing and electronics, it&#39;s super helpful to be able to round-trip between the mechanicals and the PCB layout. This can help ensure your shapes all fit the way you expect, including holes and mounting features.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Simulation capabilities. This means both things like &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LTspice&#34;&gt;LTSpice&lt;/a&gt; for electronics, but also various forms of FEM like static stress. This helps figure out how something you&#39;re designing that has to bear some amount of load (static at least) will react.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rendering. It&#39;d be nice to have some decent rendering capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Documentation capabilities. 3D models are great, but when the rubber-meets-the-road, most organizations are driven by 2D drawings. Being able to create these and have them dynamically updated will be infinitely better than my manual drafting in high school.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;For my purposes, I settled onusing&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.autodesk.com/products/fusion-360/overview?term=1-YEAR&amp;amp;tab=subscription&#34;&gt;Fusion360&lt;/a&gt;and paid for a regular subscription annually. See my discussion&lt;a href=&#34;fusion360.md&#34;&gt;elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; as to the license tradeoffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Alternatives to Fusion360&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that these are all parametric modelers. Parametric modelers use a3D modeling technique based on computational methodology to manipulatethe geometry. It happens using parameters that are (adjustable)geometric properties of a design model.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;3DEXPERIENCE SOLIDWORKS&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;$99.00 :material-update:{ title=&#34;as of 2023-6&#34; }&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xe.com/currencyconverter/convert/?Amount=99.00&amp;amp;From=USD&amp;amp;To=EUR&#34; title=&#34;Convert to other currency&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-solid-money-bill-transfer:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.solidworks.com/solution/3dexperience-solidworks-makers&#34;&gt;forMakers&lt;/a&gt;.Based on the recommendations of a friend, this is the application Istarted with. It is insanely powerful, and definitely &#34;industrial-grade&#34;tooling. The Maker edition does have some limits (such as watermarkingthings) but likely is fine for most people&#39;s use. The main reason Istopped using it is that it crashed more than I would like, and thewebsite is &lt;em&gt;impenetrable&lt;/em&gt;. Seriously, it may be the worst website I&#39;veever interacted with, and it&#39;s often necessary to get things done.There&#39;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://all3dp.com/2/fusion-360-vs-solidworks-cad-software-compared-side-by-side/&#34;&gt;comparison of Fusion360 andSOLIDWORKS&lt;/a&gt;you can read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SOLIDWORKS doesn&#39;t work on macOS, although there is a web interface for some ofthe tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;FreeCAD&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Open Source, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freecad.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;] The closest thing toSOLIDWORKS or Fusion360. And while I know a lot of people have a lot of love forthe tool, I&#39;ve not had the best of luck with it from a stability perspective. Ialso find it more difficult to use than either Fusion360 or SOLIDWORKS (whichshare a huge amount in common).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;OpenSCAD&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Open Source, &lt;a href=&#34;https://openscad.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;] Another parametricmodeler, but this one uses a scripting language to drive its modeling,rather than inferring the model from the interactive use of the system.This might be easier for some people to think about, and it encouragesyou to use parameters much more. For a starter system, though, I thinkit&#39;s not super intuitive for most people. You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/OpenSCAD_Tutorial/Chapter_1&#34;&gt;read thetutorial&lt;/a&gt; tosee how you feel about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Onshape&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Free - $2,500.00 :material-update:{ title=&#34;as of 2023-06&#34; }&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.xe.com/currencyconverter/convert/?Amount=2500.00&amp;amp;From=USD&amp;amp;To=EUR&#34; title=&#34;Convert to other currency&#34;&gt;:fontawesome-solid-money-bill-transfer:&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.onshape.com/en/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;. Despite being a web-onlyapplication, Onshape is a serious tool. Where it excels is incollaboration (obviously), even supporting simultaneous multi-userediting. The &#34;free&#34; (as in beer) version has a couple of limitationsthat make it potentially uninteresting. First, you can&#39;t use it forcommercial projects. Second, all your work will be public. Lastly,you&#39;re missing both the PCB functionality and the rendering.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Accessories to Make Your Life Better&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3&gt;SpaceMouse&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you do any amount of 3D modeling and can spare a few extra dollars,I cannot recommend the &lt;a href=&#34;https://3dconnexion.com/uk/product/spacemouse-compact/&#34;&gt;3DConnexion SpaceMouseCompact&lt;/a&gt; nearlyenough. It brings you 6 degrees-of-freedom in movement and allows you tointeract with a model as though you are holding it. While it takes a dayor two to get comfortable with, it&#39;s now second nature and a wildly moreproductive way to manipulate things.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SpaceMouse Compact&#34; src=&#34;../img/spacemouse-compact.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that it doesn&#39;t replace your mouse/trackball, but instead augments it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;El Gato StreamDeck&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harking back to the old button boxes on CAD workstations, the&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elgato.com/us/en/s/welcome-to-stream-deck&#34;&gt;StreamDeck&lt;/a&gt; maybe built for streamers, but it works great as a button box for 3Dmodeling. I have mine installed along with the SpaceMouse in a3D-printed&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/42505-spacemouse-streamdeck-mount&#34;&gt;enclosure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/modeling-tools/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/modeling-tools/</guid> </item> <item> <title>My Designs</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;My Designs&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find my designs on either&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/@petrilli_757262/models&#34;&gt;Printables&lt;/a&gt;, whichis my preferred platform for sharing, or sometimes I keep things on&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/petrilli/designs&#34;&gt;Thingiverse&lt;/a&gt; up to date.I need to be better about that!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can group things into two categories. The first is things I&#39;ve drawn up as a simple educational exercise, to show how to do things. The others are more practical or useful designs. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Educational Designs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are links to Fusion 360 designs in the cloud. You can access them in a browser, but you can also download them in a bunch of formats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://a360.co/3RsChIE&#34;&gt;Snap-fit box&lt;/a&gt;. This is a basic rectangular box with a lid and a hole in it to remove the lid. In addition to having a snap-fit lid, it also has a small &lt;a href=&#34;https://hackaday.com/2023/08/07/enhance-your-enclosures-with-a-shadow-line/&#34;&gt;shadow line&lt;/a&gt; to help improve the way it looks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Practical Designs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few things I&#39;ve put up:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/464723-watchmakers-loupe-caddy&#34;&gt;A caddy for watchmaker&#39;s loupes&lt;/a&gt;. This holds 4 different ones that often come together in 5, 10, 15, and 20X magnifications.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/468864-divider-for-organizing-a-vinyl-collection&#34;&gt;Alphabetic dividers for vinyl collections&lt;/a&gt;. These are designed to fit onto the ubiquitous IKEA KALLAX shelving that vinyl people like me love.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/496368-edsyn-soldapullt-hanger&#34;&gt;Shelf mount for an Edsyn Soldapullt&lt;/a&gt;. This allows you to mount a solder extractor to a shelf at easy reach.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/512678-label-catcher-for-brother-pt-750w&#34;&gt;Label catcher for a Brother PT-750W&lt;/a&gt;. Catch all the labels before they get away. I&#39;ve used this, in combination with the &#34;mail merge&#34; functionality in Brother&#39;s software to print hundreds of labels at a time.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/512793-interior-shelf-for-crownful-4l-mini-fridge&#34;&gt;Interior shelf for a fridge&lt;/a&gt;. This is designed to store solder paste and flux and hold it in place.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/532043-ceiling-mount-for-wera-screwdrivers-15-8mm-hex&#34;&gt;Holder for Wera hex drivers&lt;/a&gt;. Because of how my lab is oriented in the attic, I don&#39;t have a huge amount of vertical space, but I do have a 55&amp;deg; ceiling. So, I took that and mounted the screwdrivers to it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/599108-lenovo-thinkstation-p320-tiny-feet&#34;&gt;Small feet for the Lenovo Thinkstation P320 Ultra&lt;/a&gt;. This might fit other similar things, but the P320 is what I made these for. I suspect it&#39;d fit any of the small/tiny form factors.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.printables.com/model/679633-rigol-dho800900-vesa-mount-with-cable-hold&#34;&gt;VESA mount with cable strap for Rigol DHO800/900 oscilloscopes&lt;/a&gt;. The new Rigol scopes have a great feature: they can be mounted on a VESA arm. One problem is that this now puts all the cables up in a place where they can be under strain. I designed a simply mount that adds strain relief and protection for the ground connection.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/my-designs/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/my-designs/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Octoprint</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Octoprint&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;To manage and allow for web access to my &lt;a href=&#34;prusa.md&#34;&gt;3D printer&lt;/a&gt; I amrunning &lt;a href=&#34;https://octoprint.org/&#34;&gt;Octoprint&lt;/a&gt; on a cheap Intel Celeron N5105-basedmicro machine that picked up on&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aliexpress.us/item/3256802565230576.html&#34;&gt;AliExpress&lt;/a&gt; for less thanthe going rate of a decent Raspberry Pi with a case and power supply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Running on Ubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I don&#39;t run the Octoprint Raspberry Pi distribution, I had to geteverything set up myself. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Software Installation&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I created an Octoprint user (&lt;code&gt;octoprint&lt;/code&gt;) so that everything could run under anon-privileged user. Their home is &lt;code&gt;/home/octoprint&lt;/code&gt; and the software isinstalled into a Python&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.python.org/3/library/venv.html&#34;&gt;virtualenv&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;code&gt;systemd&lt;/code&gt; managing Octoprint as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/community/tutorials/understanding-systemd-units-and-unit-files&#34;&gt;serviceunit&lt;/a&gt;in &lt;code&gt;/etc/systemd/system/octoprint.service&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;```ini[Unit]Description=OctoprintAfter=network.target&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Service]ExecStart=/home/octoprint/octoprint/bin/octoprint serveWorkingDirectory=/home/octoprint/octoprintStandardOutput=inheritStandardError=inheritRestart=alwaysUser=octoprintCPUSchedulingPolicy=rrCPUSchedulingPriority=80&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Install]WantedBy=multi-user.target```&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I set &lt;code&gt;CPUSchedulingPriority&lt;/code&gt; to be relatively high to ensure that there&#39;s nevera blip in the gcode flow between it and the printer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you put that in place, you can enable them:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;console$ sudo systemctl enable octoprint$ sudo systemctl start octoprint$ systemctl status octoprint octoprint.service - Octoprint Loaded: loaded (/etc/systemd/system/octoprint.service; enabled; vendor preset: enabled) Active: active (running) since Fri 2023-06-09 21:56:00 PDT; 2 days ago Main PID: 883 (octoprint) Tasks: 37 (limit: 9138) Memory: 1.5G CPU: 57min 19.305s CGroup: /system.slice/octoprint.service 883 /home/octoprint/octoprint/bin/python3 /home/octoprint/octoprint/bin/octoprint serve&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Webcam&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DANGER: Do not leave your 3D printer unattended and leave your house. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the great things about Octoprint is being able to integrate awebcam into your workflow. This can give you both a real-time view ofwhat&#39;s going on, but also, using&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/octolapse/&#34;&gt;Octolapse&lt;/a&gt;, generatetime-lapses of the print and save them for review. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get it running on the Ubuntu distribution, I unfortunately had to use a Snapdistribution for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://snapcraft.io/mjpg-streamer&#34;&gt;mjpg-streamer&lt;/a&gt; toolthat is used. I&#39;m sure I could have gotten it running otherwise, but after a fewfalse starts, I just called &#34;done&#34; and kept moving.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like Octoprint itself, I have systemd managing the software. I used thefollowing unit file in &lt;code&gt;/etc/systemd/system/mjpg-streamer.service&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;```ini[Unit]Description=Motion JPEG StreamerAfter=network.target&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Service]ExecStart=/snap/bin/mjpg-streamer -i &#34;input_uvc.so -r 1920x1080 -f 30&#34; -o &#34;output_http.so -w /var/snap/mjpg-streamer/current/www/&#34;WorkingDirectory=/tmpStandardOutput=inheritStandardError=inheritRestart=alwaysUser=root&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Install]WantedBy=multi-user.target```&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, like with Octoprint, you can enable and start it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;console$ sudo systemctl enable mjpg-streamer$ sudo systemctl start mjpg-streamer$ systemctl status mjpg-streamer mjpg-streamer.service - Motion JPEG Streamer Loaded: loaded (/etc/systemd/system/mjpg-streamer.service; enabled; vendor preset: enabled) Active: active (running) since Fri 2023-06-09 21:56:00 PDT; 2 days ago Main PID: 882 (mjpg-streamer.s) Tasks: 0 (limit: 9138) Memory: 12.9M CPU: 913ms CGroup: /system.slice/mjpg-streamer.service  882 /bin/sh /snap/mjpg-streamer/42/bin/mjpg-streamer.sh -i &#34;input_uvc.so -r 1920x1080 -f 30&#34; -o &#34;output_&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have found these plugins to Octoprint, among the many hundreds, to beespecially useful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/bedlevelvisualizer/&#34;&gt;Bed Visualizer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/costestimation/&#34;&gt;Cost Estimation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/DisplayLayerProgress/&#34;&gt;Display Layer Progress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/excluderegion/&#34;&gt;Exclude Region&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/HeaterTimeout/&#34;&gt;Heater Timeout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/octolapse/&#34;&gt;Octolapse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/octopod/&#34;&gt;OctoPod&lt;/a&gt;. Integrates with the iOS app &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/octopod-for-octoprint/id1412557625&#34;&gt;OctoPod&lt;/a&gt; that gives you real-time access to your printer over your iOS device. It can even work on AppleTV.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/PrintJobHistory/&#34;&gt;Print Job History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/PrintTimeGenius/&#34;&gt;PrintTimeGenius&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/simpleemergencystop/&#34;&gt;Simple Emergency Stop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://plugins.octoprint.org/plugins/SpoolManager/&#34;&gt;Spool Manager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Access Anywhere via Tailscale&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;TODO: Discuss how to use Tailscale to access Octoprint from anywhere.Maybe this belongs in a whole new section for &#34;Linuxy things&#34;?&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/octoprint/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/octoprint/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Parametric Modeling</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Parameters in Parametric Models&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Naming Scheme&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Something I&#39;ve learned the hard way is that you need to have a naming schemewhen you start to do a lot of parameters in your models. Otherwise, you end upfinding it difficult to identify which parameter you&#39;re looking for. Parametersin Fusion360 can have alphanumeric characters and the following specialcharacters:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;_&lt;/code&gt; Underscore&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&#34;&lt;/code&gt; Double Quote&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; Dollar symbol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt; Degree symbol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;/code&gt; Micro symbol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;They cannot have a space, so I typically use&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Camel_case&#34;&gt;PascalCase&lt;/a&gt;. This is the scheme Iuse:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;| Name | Use || ------------ | ------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------- || &lt;code&gt;*ID&lt;/code&gt; | Inside Diameter of a circle-like thing. || &lt;code&gt;*OD&lt;/code&gt; | Outside Diameter of a circle-like thing. || &lt;code&gt;*Depth&lt;/code&gt; | The depth of a hole || &lt;code&gt;*Clearance&lt;/code&gt; | Any specific clearance that you need to think about. Note this is different than fit (see below). || &lt;code&gt;*Count&lt;/code&gt; | Number of something (e.g., holes) in a surface or body. |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition, I always create the following three parameters to allow formodeling of various &lt;a href=&#34;../mechanical/fit.md&#34;&gt;types of fit&lt;/a&gt; if something isgoing to be 3D printed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;| Name | Use || --------------- | ---------------------------------- || ClearanceFit | Allowance for a clearance fit. || TransitionFit | Allowance for a transition fit. || InterferenceFit | Allowance for an interference fit. |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Calculations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting with the May 2023 release of Fusion360, you can now use conditionaloperations in your parameters. This is covered &lt;a href=&#34;https://help.autodesk.com/view/fusion360/ENU/?guid=GUID-76272551-3275-46C4-AE4D-10D58B408C20&#34;&gt;in thereference&lt;/a&gt;.This opens up a huge new arena for exploration. For example, you could dosomething (simplified) like this for the number of holes in a hub:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;HoleCount = &lt;code&gt;if(HubOD &amp;gt;= 100mm; 7; 5)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This would set the &lt;code&gt;HoleCount&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;7&lt;/code&gt; if the &lt;code&gt;HubOD&lt;/code&gt; (hub outer diameter) isgreater than or equal to 100mm. You can also chain them together:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;HoleCount = &lt;code&gt;if(HubOD &amp;gt;= 100mm; if(HubOD &amp;gt;= 200mm; 9; 7); 5)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TIP: &lt;strong&gt;Future Enhancement&lt;/strong&gt; In the future, I&#39;ll probably combine the parametersfor various types of fit with the new &lt;code&gt;if&lt;/code&gt; function, and add a &lt;code&gt;PrintQuality&lt;/code&gt;that will allow setting the &lt;code&gt;PrintQuality&lt;/code&gt; variable to then calculate the actualfits.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Default User Parameters&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;NOTE: &lt;strong&gt;Global Parameters&lt;/strong&gt; Currently, Fusion360 doesn&#39;t have a conceptof global parameters that you can set for everything. This would beawesome to have in this case, but not yet. &lt;a href=&#34;https://productdesignonline.com/how-to-create-and-use-global-parameters-in-fusion-360/&#34;&gt;There are ways to fakeit&lt;/a&gt;,but I find them overly complicated, and the CSV file with Parameters I/Ois a much simpler solution. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most powerful things with a parametric modeling tool is beingable to create standard parameters that drive the model. Often, a lot ofthese are references to external parts that you need to interact with,like a screw. To simplify &lt;em&gt;my life&lt;/em&gt;, I have put together a CSV thatcontains:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;../mechanical/fit.md&#34;&gt;Fits for my printer&lt;/a&gt;: interference, transitional, and clearance. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Standard metric screws for M2 - M12 in all the default standard threads. This is for &lt;em&gt;socket head screws&lt;/em&gt;, which are my go-to. The insert and tap information will work for &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; metric screw of that size and thread pitch (yay metric!). These are all just &#34;standard&#34; thread pitches. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sizes for &lt;a href=&#34;joining-parts.md#threaded-inserts&#34;&gt;threaded inserts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can download the CSV from here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://lab.rebma.io/files/f360_default_parameters.csv&#34; title=&#34;Size: 4.91 KB; Updated: 2024-05-02 04:39; License: CC-BY 4.0&#34;&gt;f360_default_parameters.csv :material-download-circle-outline:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can import them quickly with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.autodesk.com/FUSION/en/Detail/Index?id=1801418194626000805&#34;&gt;ParametersI/O&lt;/a&gt;add-on that Autodesk provides (you&#39;ll need to install for some weirdreason). Once imported, if you look at user parameters, you&#39;ll seesomething like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Fusion360 user parameters dialog box showing a large number ofparameters&#34; src=&#34;../img/f360-user-parameters-imported.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The naming is based on this pattern:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;type of fit&amp;gt;Fit&amp;lt;layer height without decimal&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for the various fits.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;size&amp;gt;Head&amp;lt;OD/Depth&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for the outside diameter (OD) and depth (height) of the screw.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;size&amp;gt;InsertHoleID&lt;/code&gt; for the inside diameter (ID) of the hole you&#39;ll need to insert the insert.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;size&amp;gt;InsertDepth&lt;/code&gt; for the depth of the insert when you do an extrude cut. Note there are also some &lt;code&gt;InsertShortDepth&lt;/code&gt; for the CNC Kitchen short inserts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;size&amp;gt;TapeHoleID&lt;/code&gt; for the ID of the hole you&#39;ll need if you plan on &lt;a href=&#34;joining-parts.md#tapping-holes&#34;&gt;tapping the holes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;size&amp;gt;&amp;lt;fit&amp;gt;ClearanceHoleID&lt;/code&gt; for the clearance holes as specified in Machinery&#39;s Handbook in their normal, close, and loose fits.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve provided references to where the data came from originally (forexample, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcmaster.com/&#34;&gt;McMaster-Carr&lt;/a&gt; screw partnumbers). There&#39;s a few things you might need to do:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;You should update the fits for &lt;em&gt;your printer&lt;/em&gt;. This is just for my Prusa MINI+, and won&#39;t necessarily match yours. It&#39;s a good start if you don&#39;t want to fuss about it, although many cheap 3D printers have much bigger tolerances.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;When you want to use &lt;code&gt;M3HeadOD&lt;/code&gt; (for example), you&#39;ll want to allow for tolerance. I typically use &lt;code&gt;TransitionFit030&lt;/code&gt;, which will get a snug fit that doesn&#39;t drag when you put the screw in. To do that, when you create the circle, just set the size to &lt;code&gt;M3HeadOD + TransitionFit030&lt;/code&gt;. I didn&#39;t include the fit in the main size because different people want different fits in different situations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/parametric-parameters/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/parametric-parameters/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Prusa MINI+</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Prusa Printer&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;!-- TODO:* Different kinds of bed material* Cleaning the bed* Removing prints from the bed (let it cool, flex the spring steel)--&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, I have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prusa3d.com/category/original-prusa-mini/&#34;&gt;PrusaMINI+&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Maker&#39;s Muse Slicer Settings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use the following settings taken from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.makersmuse.com&#34;&gt;Maker&#39;sMuse&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s recommendations. These are all for&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prusa3d.com/page/prusaslicer_424/&#34;&gt;PrusaSlicer&lt;/a&gt;. I find that theygenerate a pretty reasonable draft product &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; faster than the default Prusasettings, which are quite conservative for obvious reasons. All speeds are inmm/s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;| Setting | Normal | High-Speed || -------------------------- | ------ | -------------- || Layers/Bottom solid layers | 4 | 3 || Layers/Top solid layers | 6 | 3 || Layers/Layer height | 0.20 | 0.30 || Speed/Bridges | 25 | 60 || Speed/External perimeters | 40 | 70 || Speed/Gap fill | 40 | 80 || Speed/Infill | 140 | 250 || Speed/Perimeters | 50 | 100 || Speed/Small Perimeters | 25 | 50 || Speed/Solid Infill | 140 | 250 || Speed/Support Material | 40 | 100 || Speed/Top Solid Infill | 40 | 100 || Infill/Fill Density | 20% | 10% || Infill/Fill Pattern | Grid | Adaptive Cubic |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can download the exported configuration from here:&lt;a href=&#34;https://lab.rebma.io/files/prusa-mini-fast-profile.ini&#34; title=&#34;Size: 11.34 KB; Updated: 2024-05-02 04:39; License: Public Domain&#34;&gt;prusa-mini-fast-profile.ini :material-download-circle-outline:&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Engineering Fit for MINI+&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using some test prints, I was able to determine the following types of fits thatwork for me, at least with Jessie PLA. Fit is a specific mechanical relationshipbetween (typically) a shaft and a hole. See &lt;a href=&#34;../mechanical/fit.md&#34;&gt;my discussion offit&lt;/a&gt; elsewhere for more details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;| Print Profile | Interference | Transition | Clearance | Filament || ----------------- | ------------ | ---------- | --------- | ---------- || 0.15 Quality | 0.133 mm | 0.135 | 0.175 | Jessie PLA || 0.30 Maker&#39;s Muse | 0.135 mm | 0.155 | 0.175 | Jessie PLA |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use these in Fusion360 to help &lt;a href=&#34;parametric-parameters.md&#34;&gt;parameterize the models&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/prusa/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/prusa/</guid> </item> <item> <title>SOLIDWORKS</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;SOLIDWORKS&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Useful Properties for Drawings&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When building something dynamic, I found the following properties to be usefulwhen building 2D drawings:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CompanyName&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;DrawnBy&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;DrawnDate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;CheckedBy&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;CheckedDate&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Revision&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;SOLIDWORKS also brings in the following properties from each &lt;em&gt;part&lt;/em&gt; or&lt;em&gt;assembly&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Description&lt;/code&gt; (as Title)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Weight&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Material&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Finish&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;Revision&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/solidworks/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/solidworks/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Waterproofing</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Waterproofing&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prints you get out of a FFF printer are highly unlikely to bewaterproof. If they are, it&#39;s mostly an accident. While there won&#39;t be ahuge amount of leakage, there will likely be some. For most uses, thisdoesn&#39;t matter, but it could matter if, for example, you&#39;re printing alovely vase. You need it to hold water, or the flowers will die.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To waterproof, you&#39;ve got a few options:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Epoxy resin coating. There is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TyhGxJr_A0Y&#34;&gt;Youtube video on the process&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wax (note, Gulf Wax melts at approximately 130F)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Acetone (ABS, ASA, etc. not PLA/PETG)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Silicone conformal coating (like from MG Chemicals)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Clear spray paint, like Rustoleum Universal Clear&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;TODO: Show how to use a few of these, ideally with step-by-stepinstructions. &lt;/p&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/3d/waterproofing/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/3d/waterproofing/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Electronics</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Electronics&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3rd Party Resources&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.analog.com/university&#34;&gt;Analog Devices&#39; Engineering University Program&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/electronics/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/electronics/</guid> </item> <item> <title>PCB design</title> <description></description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/electronics/PCB-design/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/electronics/PCB-design/</guid> </item> <item> <title>Connector: Basics</title> <description>&lt;h1&gt;Connector: Basics&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Contact&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Durability&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Gender&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Locking/Non-Locking&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Mount Type&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Pitch&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Polarity&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Strain Relief&lt;/h2&gt;</description><link>https://lab.rebma.io/electronics/connector-basics/</link> <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 04:38:50 -0700</pubDate><source url="https://lab.rebma.io/feed_rss_updated.xml">lab.rebma.io Notebook</source><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lab.rebma.io/electronics/connector-basics/</guid> </item> </channel></rss>